Nate King

Full Stack Developer

Full-stack developer with fifteen years of IT systems and management experience, who recently left the IT world to level up their technical prowess by becoming a developer. Years have been spent honing in on the abilities to troubleshoot, problem-solve, and think out of the box when it comes to standing out in the technology field. Whether having been working autonomously, a part of teams or leading whole departments, all challenges were met head-on and accomplished with efficiency, care, and the highest quality.

Work Experience

IT Manager

Revzilla Motorsports | Philadelphia, PA

2019 - 2020

- Responsible for full scale IT department for 450+ user base and 4 facilities across the country
- Oversaw the IT needs of full scale web development, customer service, data analytic, marketing, and retail teams located across a national setting
- Support a multi-platform environment with Windows, Mac, & Linux in both client and PM/VM servers, including SAN's
- Lead admin for GSuite, Atlassian, Slack, LucidChart, Adobe, and many other tech business related services
- \bullet Renegotiated contracts and costs of goods from ISP's and third party vendors saving thousands in IT expenses
- Implemented a backup server solution in a facility that ran with no disaster recovery procedures
- Updated network to bring into PCI compliance
- Work side by side with web development team and DevOps teams

IT Systems Administrator

PRG Real Estate | Philadelphia, PA

2013 - 2019

- Provided IT system administration support via Level's 1,2, and 3 for PA based property management firm with national offices and a 300+ user base
- Acted as an implementation specialist for user support of the nation's leading property management software Yardi
- Operation and administration to multiple versions of Windows servers as well as AD, Office 365, Azure, and SharePoint
- Fully migrated and setup legacy server infrastructure from outdated physical hardware to virtual Hyper V environment in a failover cluster with multiple layers of redundancy on and off site
- Planned, organized, and executed a project to migrate SharePoint 2010 server to Office 365 cloud environment

Contact Details

215.828.5606

□ natemking@gmail.com

www.natemking.dev

github.com/natemking

in linkedin.com/in/natemking

Philadelphia, PA

Tech Skills

Languages

JavaScript

HTML

CSS

MySQL

PowerShell

Frameworks

MongoDB

Express.js

React.js

Node.js

iQuery

BootStrap

Other Skills

Windows/OS X/Linux Server administration Atlassian Admin Azure/Cloud Services

Hyper V/XenServer/VM

AD, DNS, DHCP

O365 & GSuite administration Cisco & general networks

TCP/IP

Personal Skills

Project management
Team leading/management
Meticulous Documentation
Client relations
Highly organized
Bookkeeping

- Acting liaison with multiple service providers to get the best deals in order to save the company money and improve efficiency
- Remote administration and setup of all users PC's. Brought entire corporation to domain architecture and implemented standards and practices never seen at PRG via group policy
- Traveled to multiple offices across the country to provide onsite installation, support, maintenance, and training for both hardware and software architecture
- Ran tech call center operations with a skill for effectively communicating with technical and non-technical staff as well as 3rd party consultants
- Onsite and remote PC repair. Implemented imaging process to streamline PC rollout efficiency

Lead Desktop Support Technician

Premier Orthopaedics | Newtown Square, PA 2013

- Provided support via Level's 1,2, and 3 IT infrastructure for leading southeast Orthopedic group
- Maintained support for NextGen & Allscripts EHR software deployed via terminal server
- Maintained support on both PC and server side of PACS system
- \bullet Operation and administration to $\,$ multiple Windows 2008 servers including AD and Exchange support
- Assisted implementation and began companywide rollout of Windows 7 deployment
- Experience with full migration of local EHR software to terminal server system
- Worked to keep all corporate systems within HIPAA compliance
- Provided remote desktop support to end users to effectively resolve their issues

Network Technician / Asset & Supply Manager

Campus Technologies Inc | Philadelphia, PA 2005 - 2012

Additional Experience

Cultivation Technician

Agri-Kind | Chester, PA

- Support Master Grower by using past knowledge of plants to perform duties such as, but not limited to, plant tending, transplanting, feeding, defoliation, topping, flushing, inventory management, waste management, etc...
- Specialized in the fertigation system maintenance and operations. Developed and established a fertigation department along with best practices for the department.
- Responsible for nutrient replenishment in the automated fertigation system on a daily basis as well as making sure the nutrient mix is balanced and pH'ed per the Master Growers specifications in the mother, veg, and bloom stages.

Example Projects

Google Book Search

http://bit.ly/book-nmk-git **Deploy** -

http://bit.ly/book-nmk-prod

About - PWA that you can search for books using the Google Books API & save them to your library.

Duties - Front-End - React. Backend server, routing, & database code

Tech - HTML, CSS, BootStrap, Javascript, Node.js, Express.js, MongoDB, React

Follow Your Money GitHub -

http://bit.ly/fym-nmk-git **Deploy** - http://bit.ly/fym-nmk-prod

About - Easy finance tracker with charts and categorical spending

Duties - Front-End design & JS dynamics. Backend server routing, & database code

Tech - HTML, CSS, Javascript, Node.js, Express.js, MongoDB, Mongoose, Webpack

Education

University of Pennsylvania's LPS Coding Accelerated Learning Program

2020 - 2021 Certificate in Full Stack Web Development